{
  "1": {
    "question": "Give me an example of the project or initiative that you started on your own. It can be a non-business one. What prompted you to get started?",
    "answer": "On one of my earlier group projects using RESTful APIs we were having difficulty accessing the specific API in the way that we wanted. I took the intiative to contact the team workin on the API and was able to get guidance. Funnily enough, not only did I get our project working, but the API documentation was changed to cover cases like ours, so they ended up better off for it as well."
  },
  "2": {
    "question": "Tell me about a time you had to work on several projects at once. How did you handle it?",
    "answer": "When freelancing its not uncommon to work on numberous client projects simultaneously. I learned early on that it was best to break everything down into sub-tasks and set them to different priorities: low, mid, or high. I now have a much better understanding of expected deadlines, and how to assign priorities to tasks and sub-tasks with that in mind."
  },
  "3": {
    "question": "Describe a situation in which you felt you had not communicated well enough. What did you do? How did you handle it?",
    "answer": "When I first began working with other developers I was told to create a pretty basic function, but unfortunately I misunderstood what the function was supposed to do. I had to ask the Tech Lead for clarification, but now, to ensure complete understanding, even if I think I know exactly what is being asked of me I always verify."
  },
  "4": {
    "question": "Tell me about when you had to deal with conflict within your team. How was the conflict solved? How did you handle that? How would you deal with it now? ",
    "answer": ""
  },
  "5": {
    "question": "Give me an example of a time you had to take a creative and unusual approach to solve a coding problem. How did this idea come to your mind? Why do you think it was unusual?",
    "answer": ""
  },
  "6": {
    "question": "Describe a situation in which you worked diligently on a project and it did not produce the desired results. Why didn't you get the desired results? What did you learn from the experience?",
    "answer": "When I first started building webpages I had an unsatisfied client, yet I had built exactly what they had asked for. I scheduled a meeting with them to go over the contract, compare that to the finished product, and recontract some work to get things to the result that they wanted. Because of this I often do mock-ups to ensure the client is completely clear with what they will be receiving as a final product, and haven't encountered any issues since."
  },
  "7": {
    "question": "Give an example of an important project goal you reached and how you achieved it.",
    "answer": "One of my most important project goals was creating and building my first MERN app. It was a goal from the very start of my programming journey, and it took countless hours of independent research to achieve. This often included reaching out in the tech community and asking for guidance from my mentors. Ultimately I created [one of your amazing apps]"
  },
  "8": {
    "question": "Describe a situation in which you experienced difficulty in getting others to accept your ideas.",
    "answer": ""
  },
  "9": {
    "question": "Tell me about a situation when you were responsible for project planning. Did everything go according to plan? If not, then why and what kind of counteractions did you have to take?",
    "answer": "I was in charge of a group working on updating old legacy code, and it didn't all work as I initially planned as I didn't set proper variable naming conventions for the project. This resulted in us having a good amount of unforseen errors and bugs, but after the errors were noticed I worked to create a coding convention for our group so we could all work together with the same standards."
  },
  "10": {
    "question": "Tell me about a situation when you made a mistake at work. What happened exactly and how did you deal with it? What steps did you take to improve the situation?",
    "answer": "While I was creating a webpage for a client I accidentally created a link that sent you to a the wrong page. I had to contact the client to notify them that we needed to make a quick change. Fortunately the turnaround was incredibly quick, and as a new business they hadn't sent anyone to their new website yet. I learned to always double-check interactable things like links to ensure not only that they are working, but that they are working as intended."
  },
  "11": {
    "question": "Tell me about a time when you worked with someone who was not completing his or her share of the work. How did you handle the situation? Did you discuss your concern with your coworker? With your manager? If yes, how did your coworker respond to your concern? What was your manager's response?",
    "answer": "I've noticed in past experiences that when people aren't completing their share of work it usually isn't out of laziness, but rather just a lack of direction or understanding. Any time I notice a coworker under-performing in such a manner I engage with them in a short discussion about what they're working on and focus on the task. A better understanding of how to address an issue almost always results in increased performance."
  },
  "12": {
    "question": "Describe a situation when you worked effectively under pressure. How did you feel when working under pressure? What was going on, and how did you get through it?",
    "answer": "I often have to work with multiple clients simultaneously and under tight deadlines. This can lead to a good deal of pressure as every client wants their concerns addressed immediately. I always start by assuring the client that they are a priority and that I will fix their issues as soon as possible."
  },
  "13": {
    "question": "Tell me about yourself",
    "answer": "I'm a Software Engineer that started learning Java in the early 2000's. I took a break from programming and spent a decade in the U.S. Army travelling the world and picking up other skills. After transitioning from the Army I began working as a freelance Web Developer, and I'm currently interested in developing my skills even further by working on challenging new problems with intelligent forward-thinking individuals."
  },
  "14": {
    "question": "Tell me about your experience at 100Devs",
    "answer": "My experience at 100Devs was pretty amazing overall. My primary focus was on learning coding, but I picked up a lot of secondary skills along the way, such as navigating contracts, working directly with clients, and how to work on projects in a group using Agile methodology. 100Devs was both incredibly difficult and rewarding."
  },
  "15": {
    "question": "What do you know about our company?",
    "answer": "I know that your company uses [tech stacks], I know that your product [product] is a powerful tool that does [thing]. I know from talking to [referral] that you guys have a great work environment, with intelligent programmers working together to provide solutions to complex problems."
  },
  "16": {
    "question": "Why do you want to work for us?",
    "answer": "MONEY! Just kidding. Based on what I see of [company/product] and the tech stack you guys use I am thrilled at the thought of working with your team and that tech! I know [referral name here], so I know I'd already be working amongst great thinkers and developers, and this company would be a great place for me to flex my skills and show my talents as a Software Engineer."
  },
  "17": {
    "question": "Why are you interested in this opportunity?",
    "answer": "I'm interested in this opportunity because of the incredible product that your Software Engineers work on. I see the all the great things you guys are doing at [company name] and I love what I see. I'm looking forward for an opportunity to leverage my skills to assist in the creation, maintenance, and improvement of applications here!"
  },
  "18": {
    "question": "Tell me about your dream job? What do you really want to do with your career?",
    "answer": "My dream job is a place where I can write code, interact with other programmers and their work, and work in a positive/encouraging environment. I love discussing code with others, combining my work with other code to form one singlar powerful product, and I thoroughly enjoy a good challenge. All of these are things I think working here will provide, and having met some of the programmers[referral name here] on the team I am confident I would thrive in this environment."
  },
  "19": {
    "question": "Tell me about a time when you failed.",
    "answer": "Ok. I still feel bad about this one, but I was asked to work on some code and we were supposed to push to production and be done for the week. Unfortunately in the middle of the weekend the product crashed and we had major issues. Following that we implemented fail-safes, such as not pushing to production on Fridays, and we also began practicing peer-reviewed code"
  },
  "20": {
    "question": "What do you read on a regular basis?",
    "answer": "I read to relax, so I often find myself reading about things in the tech community. From reading about new and emerging tech, to reading about different implementation of old tech, I love it all! In fact, just the other day I was reading an incredible article about [topic here]{the Quake 3 Inverse Square Root algorithm}!"
  },
  "21": {
    "question": "What is some critical feedback you've gotten recently?",
    "answer": "I have gotten some feedback about improving soeme design choices recently. Working directly with clients without a designer on hand leaves some of the aesthetics open to interpretation. I began using new tools to help me overcome these issues, like palette generators, and I took a brief course in web-page design to shore this weakness up."
  },
  "22": {
    "question": "Do you have any questions?",
    "answer": "Save questions for after you get an offer! Be glad! You've got this and you're making great strides towards success!"
  },
  "rip": {
    "question": "There seems to be some kind of issue",
    "answer": "Please notify admin at mingleeng@gmail.com"
  }
}
